andrea benfatto

Karl-Marx-Allee 85 • 10243 Berlin • Germany CELL (+49) 157 788 811 12 • E-MAIL andreabenfatto@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineer • 9 years of experience

I have a broad experience ranging from backend and frontend development to infrastructure, operations automation and mentoring.

Having worked not only in startups, and being used to wear a few different hats, I try to have an impact on organisations that goes beyond engineering.

I value autonomy, a quality driven mindset, effective communication, and business sensitive engineering solutions.

I am always eager to learn new things and take great pleasure in teaching things to others.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Red Pineapple Media GmbH

April 2015 - July 2018

Keywords Site Reliability Engineer, Docker, Ansible, SRE, AWS ECS, Jenkins, Clojure, PHP, Bash, MySQL, Elasticsearch, Cassandra

- · Logging, monitoring and alerting optimisation.
- Performance optimisation to scale traffic and reduce costs.
- Migrate from monolith to micro-services using Docker + ECS.
- Automate all the things.
- Introduced containers and mentor the team on the subject.
- Design strategy to incrementally replace legacy PHP application using micro-services.
- Promote good practices related to REST APIs, security, distributed systems design, automated testing, version control history, documenting of failures and outages.
- Developed product features as implement industry standard APIs (OpenRTB - VAST).

Software Engineer - Freelancing

June 2014 - March 2015

Keywords Scala, Golang, Angular 2, Python, Digitalocean

- Maintain existing CRM/ERP solution.
- Introduce provisioning scripts to generated spot environments on the cloud to test purposes.

Fullstack Developer & UX/UI Designer - Spotistic UG

November 2013 - May 2014

Keywords Ruby, JavaScript, MongoDB, Redis, Sidekiq

- Build the first version of the responsive website.
- Mentor the team on UX and frontend practices.
- Design and implement APIs to serve multiple frontends
- Sidekiq tasks and backend development.

Software Engineer - Performer SPA

January 2013 - September 2013

Keywords HTML5, JS, CSS3, Phonegap,

• Hybrid mobile development.

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Alma Mater Studiorum - Università di Bologna Via Zamboni, 33, 40126 Bologna BO, Italy 2001 - 2003

I successfully passed more than half of the classes but I couldn't continue to the degree for personal reasons.